{
  "published_book": {
    "content": [
      {
        "chapter": "Chapter 1",
        "end": 2,
        "length": 1,
        "pages": [
          [
            {
              "POS": [
                "NOUN",
                "PUNCT"
              ],
              "labels": [
                "I-MISC",
                "O"
              ],
              "text": "States ."
            },
            {
              "POS": [
                "SCONJ",
                "ADP",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "NOUN",
                "CCONJ",
                "NOUN",
                "NOUN",
                "PRON",
                "AUX",
                "VERB",
                "VERB",
                "DET",
                "ADJ",
                "NOUN",
                "ADJ",
                "ADP",
                "PRON",
                "ADJ",
                "ADP",
                "ADJ",
                "NOUN",
                "PUNCT",
                "PROPN",
                "PROPN",
                "VERB",
                "DET",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "ADJ",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "PROPN",
                "PUNCT"
              ],
              "labels": [
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-MISC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-PER",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-LOC",
                "O"
              ],
              "text": "Although as secretary of state and vice president he had opposed developing an American navy capable of anything more than coastal defense , President Jefferson dispatched a squadron of naval vessels to the Mediterranean ."
            },
            {
              "POS": [
                "SCONJ",
                "PRON",
                "VERB",
                "ADP",
                "PRON",
                "ADJ",
                "ADJ",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "PROPN",
                "PUNCT",
                "PUNCT",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "ADJ",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "PRON",
                "PRON",
                "AUX",
                "AUX",
                "VERB",
                "PUNCT",
                "NUM",
                "ADJ",
                "NOUN",
                "VERB",
                "PUNCT"
              ],
              "labels": [
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-ORG",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O"
              ],
              "text": "As he declared in his first annual message to Congress : \" To this state of general peace with which we have been blessed , one only exception exists ."
            },
            {
              "POS": [
                "PROPN",
                "PUNCT",
                "DET",
                "ADJ",
                "ADJ",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "PROPN",
                "PROPN",
                "PUNCT",
                "AUX",
                "VERB",
                "ADV",
                "ADP",
                "NOUN",
                "ADJ",
                "CCONJ",
                "ADP",
                "NOUN",
                "CCONJ",
                "ADP",
                "ADJ",
                "PUNCT",
                "CCONJ",
                "AUX",
                "VERB",
                "PRON",
                "PART",
                "VERB",
                "NOUN",
                "PUNCT",
                "ADP",
                "PRON",
                "NOUN",
                "PART",
                "VERB",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "VERB",
                "NOUN",
                "PUNCT"
              ],
              "labels": [
                "I-LOC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-LOC",
                "I-MISC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O"
              ],
              "text": "Tripoli , the least considerable of the Barbary States , had come forward with demands unfounded either in right or in compact , and had permitted itself to denounce war , on our failure to comply before a given day ."
            },
            {
              "POS": [
                "DET",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "NOUN",
                "VERB",
                "CCONJ",
                "NUM",
                "NOUN",
                "PUNCT"
              ],
              "labels": [
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O"
              ],
              "text": "The style of the demand admitted but one answer ."
            },
            {
              "POS": [
                "PRON",
                "VERB",
                "DET",
                "ADJ",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "PROPN",
                "PUNCT"
              ],
              "labels": [
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-LOC",
                "O"
              ],
              "text": "I sent a small squadron of frigates into the Mediterranean ."
            },
            {
              "POS": [
                "PUNCT"
              ],
              "labels": [
                "O"
              ],
              "text": "."
            },
            {
              "POS": [
                "PUNCT"
              ],
              "labels": [
                "O"
              ],
              "text": "."
            },
            {
              "POS": [
                "PUNCT",
                "PUNCT",
                "DET",
                "ADJ",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "NOUN",
                "ADV",
                "VERB",
                "PROPN",
                "CCONJ",
                "PROPN",
                "ADP",
                "VERB",
                "PRON",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "PROPN",
                "PUNCT"
              ],
              "labels": [
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-MISC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-LOC",
                "O",
                "I-LOC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-LOC",
                "O"
              ],
              "text": ". \" The American show of force quickly awed Tunis and Algiers into breaking their alliance with Tripoli ."
            },
            {
              "POS": [
                "DET",
                "ADJ",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "ADJ",
                "PROPN",
                "CCONJ",
                "DET",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "PRON",
                "NOUN",
                "CCONJ",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "PROPN",
                "ADP",
                "NUM",
                "PUNCT",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "PRON",
                "ADJ",
                "NOUN",
                "PUNCT",
                "CCONJ",
                "ADV",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "PRON",
                "ADJ",
                "NOUN",
                "AUX",
                "PART",
                "VERB",
                "PROPN",
                "ADP",
                "PRON",
                "VERB",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "NUM",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "NOUN",
                "PUNCT"
              ],
              "labels": [
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-LOC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-LOC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-PER",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O"
              ],
              "text": "The humiliating loss of the frigate Philadelphia and the capture of her captain and crew in Tripoli in 1803 , criticism from his political opponents , and even opposition within his own cabinet did not deter Jefferson from his chosen course during four years of war ."
            },
            {
              "POS": [
                "DET",
                "ADJ",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "PROPN",
                "PROPN",
                "PROPN",
                "PUNCT",
                "NUM",
                "SYM",
                "NUM",
                "PUNCT",
                "VERB",
                "PROPN",
                "ADP",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "NOUN",
                "CCONJ",
                "PRON",
                "NUM",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "PROPN",
                "VERB",
                "DET",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "PROPN",
                "PUNCT"
              ],
              "labels": [
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-PER",
                "I-PER",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-LOC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-LOC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-LOC",
                "O"
              ],
              "text": "The aggressive action of Commodore Edward Preble ( 1803 - 4 ) forced Morocco out of the fight and his five bombardments of Tripoli restored some order to the Mediterranean ."
            },
            {
              "POS": [
                "ADV",
                "PUNCT",
                "PRON",
                "AUX",
                "PART",
                "ADP",
                "NUM",
                "PUNCT",
                "SCONJ",
                "DET",
                "ADJ",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "PROPN",
                "PROPN",
                "PROPN",
                "CCONJ",
                "DET",
                "NOUN",
                "NOUN",
                "VERB",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "ADJ",
                "ADJ",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "PROPN",
                "NOUN",
                "PUNCT",
                "PROPN",
                "PROPN",
                "PROPN",
                "PUNCT",
                "VERB",
                "PART",
                "VERB",
                "PROPN",
                "CCONJ",
                "VERB",
                "DET",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "PROPN",
                "PART",
                "PROPN",
                "PROPN",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "NOUN",
                "PUNCT",
                "SCONJ",
                "DET",
                "NOUN",
                "VERB",
                "DET",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "NOUN",
                "PUNCT"
              ],
              "labels": [
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-MISC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-PER",
                "I-PER",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-MISC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-MISC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-PER",
                "I-PER",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-LOC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-LOC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O"
              ],
              "text": "However , it was not until 1805 , when an American fleet under Commodore John Rogers and a land force raised by an American naval agent to the Barbary powers , Captain William Eaton , threatened to capture Tripoli and install the brother of Tripoli ' s pasha on the throne , that a treaty brought an end to the hostilities ."
            },
            {
              "POS": [
                "VERB",
                "ADP",
                "PROPN",
                "PROPN",
                "PUNCT",
                "ADJ",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "PROPN",
                "PROPN",
                "CCONJ",
                "ADV",
                "NOUN",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "PROPN",
                "PUNCT",
                "DET",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "NUM",
                "ADV",
                "VERB",
                "DET",
                "PROPN",
                "PROPN",
                "PART",
                "VERB",
                "DET",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "SYM",
                "NUM",
                "PUNCT",
                "NUM",
                "ADP",
                "PRON",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "NOUN",
                "VERB",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "PROPN",
                "PUNCT",
                "CCONJ",
                "ADV",
                "PRON",
                "VERB",
                "ADP",
                "ADJ",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "PROPN",
                "NUM",
                "PUNCT"
              ],
              "labels": [
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-PER",
                "I-PER",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-PER",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-LOC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-LOC",
                "I-LOC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-LOC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O"
              ],
              "text": "Negotiated by Tobias Lear , former secretary to President Washington and now consul general in Algiers , the treaty of 1805 still required the United States to pay a ransom of $ 60 , 000 for each of the sailors held by the dey of Algiers , and so it went without Senatorial consent until April 1806 ."
            },
            {
              "POS": [
                "ADV",
                "PUNCT",
                "PROPN",
                "AUX",
                "ADJ",
                "PART",
                "VERB",
                "ADP",
                "PRON",
                "ADJ",
                "ADJ",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "PROPN",
                "ADP",
                "PROPN",
                "NUM",
                "SCONJ",
                "ADP",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "ADJ",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "PROPN",
                "CCONJ",
                "PROPN",
                "NOUN",
                "PUNCT",
                "PUNCT",
                "DET",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "PROPN",
                "VERB",
                "ADV",
                "VERB",
                "ADP",
                "NOUN",
                "PART",
                "VERB",
                "PRON",
                "NOUN",
                "CCONJ",
                "NOUN",
                "PUNCT",
                "PUNCT",
                "ADP",
                "NOUN",
                "PUNCT",
                "PRON",
                "AUX",
                "PART",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "ADJ",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "PROPN",
                "PUNCT",
                "ADP",
                "NUM",
                "PUNCT",
                "SCONJ",
                "ADJ",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "PROPN",
                "PROPN",
                "PROPN",
                "CCONJ",
                "PROPN",
                "PROPN",
                "VERB",
                "ADP",
                "NOUN",
                "VERB",
                "DET",
                "NOUN",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "PROPN",
                "PROPN",
                "PUNCT"
              ],
              "labels": [
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-PER",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-ORG",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-MISC",
                "I-MISC",
                "I-MISC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-LOC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-LOC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-PER",
                "I-PER",
                "O",
                "I-PER",
                "I-PER",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-LOC",
                "I-LOC",
                "O"
              ],
              "text": "Nevertheless , Jefferson was able to report in his sixth annual message to Congress in December 1806 that in addition to the successful completion of the Lewis and Clark expedition , \" The states on the coast of Barbary seem generally disposed at present to respect our peace and friendship . \" In fact , it was not until the second war with Algiers , in 1815 , that naval victories by Commodores William Bainbridge and Stephen Decatur led to treaties ending all tribute payments by the United States ."
            },
            {
              "POS": [
                "ADJ",
                "NOUN",
                "VERB",
                "ADJ",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "NOUN",
                "PUNCT"
              ],
              "labels": [
                "I-MISC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O"
              ],
              "text": "European nations continued annual payments until the 1830s ."
            },
            {
              "POS": [
                "ADV",
                "PUNCT",
                "ADJ",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "PROPN",
                "CCONJ",
                "PROPN",
                "NOUN",
                "VERB",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "PROPN",
                "PUNCT",
                "ADJ",
                "NOUN",
                "PUNCT",
                "PRON",
                "ADV",
                "ADV",
                "VERB",
                "NOUN",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "ADJ",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "NOUN",
                "CCONJ",
                "ADJ",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "NOUN",
                "PUNCT"
              ],
              "labels": [
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-LOC",
                "O",
                "I-LOC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-MISC",
                "I-MISC",
                "I-MISC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O"
              ],
              "text": "However , international piracy in Atlantic and Mediterranean waters declined during this time under pressure from the Euro - American nations , who no longer viewed pirate states as mere annoyances during peacetime and potential allies during war ."
            },
            {
              "POS": [
                "ADP",
                "PRON",
                "ADJ",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "ADJ",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "PROPN",
                "PART",
                "PART",
                "ADJ",
                "ADJ",
                "PUNCT",
                "ADJ",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "ADJ",
                "NOUN",
                "PUNCT",
                "DET",
                "PROPN",
                "PROPN",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "PROPN",
                "ADP",
                "PROPN",
                "VERB",
                "NOUN",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "ADJ",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "ADJ",
                "NOUN",
                "PUNCT",
                "VERB",
                "PROPN",
                "PROPN",
                "PUNCT",
                "PROPN",
                "PROPN",
                "PUNCT",
                "VERB",
                "DET",
                "PROPN",
                "PROPN",
                "PROPN",
                "PUNCT",
                "PUNCT",
                "PROPN",
                "PROPN",
                "PUNCT",
                "PROPN",
                "PROPN",
                "PUNCT",
                "PROPN",
                "PROPN",
                "PUNCT",
                "PROPN",
                "PROPN",
                "PUNCT",
                "PROPN",
                "PROPN",
                "PUNCT",
                "PROPN",
                "PROPN",
                "PROPN",
                "PUNCT",
                "PROPN",
                "PROPN",
                "PUNCT",
                "PROPN",
                "PROPN",
                "PUNCT",
                "PROPN",
                "PROPN",
                "PUNCT",
                "PROPN",
                "PROPN",
                "PUNCT",
                "CCONJ",
                "PROPN",
                "PROPN",
                "PUNCT"
              ],
              "labels": [
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-LOC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-ORG",
                "I-ORG",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-ORG",
                "I-ORG",
                "I-ORG",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-MISC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-PER",
                "I-PER",
                "O",
                "I-PER",
                "I-PER",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-MISC",
                "I-PER",
                "I-MISC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-PER",
                "I-PER",
                "O",
                "I-PER",
                "I-PER",
                "O",
                "I-PER",
                "I-PER",
                "O",
                "I-PER",
                "I-PER",
                "O",
                "I-PER",
                "I-PER",
                "O",
                "I-PER",
                "I-PER",
                "I-PER",
                "O",
                "I-PER",
                "I-PER",
                "O",
                "I-PER",
                "I-PER",
                "O",
                "I-PER",
                "I-PER",
                "O",
                "I-PER",
                "I-PER",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-PER",
                "I-PER",
                "O"
              ],
              "text": "For anyone interested in the further pursuit of information about America ' s first unconventional , international war in the primary sources , the Manuscript Division of the Library of Congress holds manuscript collections of many of the American participants , including Thomas Jefferson , George Washington ( see the George Washington Papers ) , William Short , Edward Preble , Thomas Barclay , James Madison , James Simpson , James Leander Cathcart , William Bainbridge , James Barron , John Rodgers , Ralph Izard , and Albert Gallatin ."
            },
            {
              "POS": [
                "NOUN",
                "PUNCT",
                "VERB",
                "NUM",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "NUM",
                "CCONJ",
                "ADJ",
                "NOUN",
                "PART",
                "VERB",
                "ADP",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "NOUN",
                "PUNCT"
              ],
              "labels": [
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O"
              ],
              "text": "Vocabulary : Pick 10 words of 3 or more syllables to define as part of the assignment ."
            },
            {
              "POS": [
                "NOUN",
                "PUNCT",
                "X",
                "PUNCT",
                "DET",
                "NOUN",
                "AUX",
                "PROPN",
                "VERB",
                "SCONJ",
                "PRON",
                "VERB",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "PROPN",
                "NOUN",
                "PUNCT"
              ],
              "labels": [
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-PER",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-MISC",
                "O",
                "O"
              ],
              "text": "Questions : 1 ) What precedent did Jefferson set when he took action against the Barbary pirates ?"
            },
            {
              "POS": [
                "X",
                "PUNCT",
                "SCONJ",
                "AUX",
                "PROPN",
                "VERB",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "PROPN",
                "PROPN",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "NOUN",
                "PUNCT"
              ],
              "labels": [
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-LOC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-MISC",
                "I-ORG",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O"
              ],
              "text": "2 ) How had Europe dealt with the Barbary Pirates in the past ?"
            },
            {
              "POS": [
                "X",
                "PUNCT",
                "SCONJ",
                "AUX",
                "PROPN",
                "VERB",
                "PRON",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "NOUN",
                "PUNCT"
              ],
              "labels": [
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-PER",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O"
              ],
              "text": "3 ) How did Jefferson reason his actions toward the pirates ?"
            },
            {
              "POS": [
                "X",
                "PUNCT",
                "SCONJ",
                "AUX",
                "DET",
                "NOUN",
                "VERB",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "NOUN",
                "PUNCT"
              ],
              "labels": [
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O"
              ],
              "text": "4 ) How did the war go with the pirates ?"
            },
            {
              "POS": [
                "X",
                "PUNCT",
                "PRON",
                "ADV",
                "VERB",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "PROPN",
                "PUNCT"
              ],
              "labels": [
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-LOC",
                "O"
              ],
              "text": "5 ) What finally brought victory to America ?"
            },
            {
              "POS": [
                "X",
                "PUNCT",
                "ADJ",
                "NOUN",
                "PUNCT",
                "SCONJ",
                "AUX",
                "DET",
                "NOUN",
                "ADJ",
                "ADP",
                "PROPN",
                "PUNCT"
              ],
              "labels": [
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-LOC",
                "O"
              ],
              "text": "6 ) Critical Thinking : Why was the war good for America ?"
            },
            {
              "POS": [
                "X",
                "PUNCT",
                "ADJ",
                "NOUN",
                "PUNCT",
                "SCONJ",
                "AUX",
                "PRON",
                "VERB",
                "DET",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "NOUN",
                "PUNCT",
                "ADV",
                "SCONJ",
                "AUX",
                "PRON",
                "VERB",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "ADJ",
                "NOUN",
                "PUNCT"
              ],
              "labels": [
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O"
              ],
              "text": "7 ) Critical Thinking : How did it expand the power of the president , finally how did it define defense of country for a young nation ?"
            },
            {
              "POS": [
                "NUM"
              ],
              "labels": [
                "O"
              ],
              "text": "2"
            }
          ]
        ],
        "start": -1
      }
    ]
  },
  "book_index": "[{\"header\":\"Chapter 1\",\"page\":\"0\"}]"
}