{
  "published_book": {
    "content": [
      {
        "chapter": "Chapter 1",
        "end": 1,
        "length": 1,
        "pages": [
          [
            {
              "POS": [
                "DET",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "PROPN",
                "CCONJ",
                "DET",
                "DET",
                "ADJ",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "NOUN",
                "VERB",
                "DET",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "PROPN",
                "AUX",
                "VERB",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "PROPN",
                "PROPN",
                "ADP",
                "PROPN",
                "CCONJ",
                "PROPN",
                "PUNCT",
                "PROPN",
                "PROPN",
                "PUNCT"
              ],
              "labels": [
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-ORG",
                "I-ORG",
                "O",
                "I-ORG",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-LOC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-ORG",
                "I-ORG",
                "I-ORG",
                "I-ORG",
                "I-ORG",
                "I-ORG",
                "O",
                "I-PER",
                "I-PER",
                "O"
              ],
              "text": "THE ROUTES OF THE RĀDHĀNĪYA AND THE The earliest description of the routes linking the provinces of the empire to Baghdad was written by the director of the Abbasid Bureau of Posts and Intelligence , Ibn Khurradādhbih ."
            },
            {
              "POS": [
                "PRON",
                "VERB",
                "DET",
                "ADJ",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "PRON",
                "PROPN",
                "ADP",
                "PROPN",
                "CCONJ",
                "PROPN",
                "ADP",
                "NUM",
                "PUNCT",
                "CCONJ",
                "PRON",
                "VERB",
                "NOUN",
                "VERB",
                "ADV",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "ADJ",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "ADJ",
                "NOUN",
                "PUNCT"
              ],
              "labels": [
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-MISC",
                "I-MISC",
                "I-MISC",
                "I-MISC",
                "I-MISC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O"
              ],
              "text": "He completed the final version of his Book of Roads and Kingdoms in 885 , but it contains material dating back to the early decades of the ninth century ."
            },
            {
              "POS": [
                "NUM",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "ADJ",
                "NOUN",
                "AUX",
                "DET",
                "ADJ",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "NUM",
                "NOUN",
                "VERB",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "ADJ",
                "NOUN",
                "VERB",
                "DET",
                "PROPN",
                "ADP",
                "PRON",
                "NOUN",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "PUNCT",
                "DET",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "PROPN",
                "PUNCT",
                "ADP",
                "PROPN",
                "CCONJ",
                "ADV",
                "PUNCT"
              ],
              "labels": [
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-MISC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-ORG",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-MISC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-LOC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O"
              ],
              "text": "One of these early documents is a succinct description of four routes followed by an organization of Jewish merchants called the Rādhānīya on their trading journeys from ‘ the land of the Franks ’ to China and back ."
            },
            {
              "POS": [
                "PRON",
                "AUX",
                "ADJ",
                "PUNCT",
                "VERB",
                "PROPN",
                "PUNCT",
                "ADJ",
                "PUNCT",
                "PROPN",
                "PUNCT",
                "PUNCT",
                "ADJ",
                "PUNCT",
                "PUNCT",
                "PUNCT",
                "ADJ",
                "PUNCT",
                "CCONJ",
                "PROPN",
                "PUNCT"
              ],
              "labels": [
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-MISC",
                "O",
                "I-MISC",
                "O",
                "I-MISC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-MISC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-MISC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-MISC",
                "O"
              ],
              "text": "They were multilingual , speaking Arabic , Persian , Greek , ‘ Frankish ’ , ‘ Andalusian ’ and Slavic ."
            },
            {
              "POS": [
                "PRON",
                "VERB",
                "NOUN",
                "PUNCT",
                "NOUN",
                "NOUN",
                "CCONJ",
                "NOUN",
                "PUNCT",
                "NOUN",
                "PUNCT",
                "NOUN",
                "CCONJ",
                "NOUN",
                "PUNCT",
                "CCONJ",
                "VERB",
                "ADJ",
                "NOUN",
                "CCONJ",
                "NOUN",
                "ADV",
                "ADP",
                "PUNCT",
                "PROPN",
                "PUNCT",
                "PUNCT",
                "DET",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "PROPN",
                "PUNCT"
              ],
              "labels": [
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-LOC",
                "I-LOC",
                "I-LOC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-MISC",
                "O"
              ],
              "text": "They exported eunuchs , slave girls and boys , brocades , furs and swords , and brought eastern spices and aromatics back to ‘ Ifrānja ’ , the land of the Franks ."
            },
            {
              "POS": [
                "PROPN",
                "PROPN",
                "PUNCT",
                "PART",
                "NOUN",
                "AUX",
                "ADJ",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "VERB",
                "ADJ",
                "PUNCT",
                "NOUN",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "PROPN",
                "CCONJ",
                "DET",
                "NOUN",
                "PUNCT",
                "PRON",
                "ADP",
                "NOUN",
                "CCONJ",
                "NOUN",
                "PUNCT",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "NOUN",
                "SCONJ",
                "PUNCT",
                "PRON",
                "AUX",
                "ADV",
                "VERB",
                "PUNCT",
                "NOUN",
                "ADV",
                "VERB",
                "ADP",
                "PROPN",
                "SCONJ",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "ADJ",
                "NOUN",
                "PUNCT"
              ],
              "labels": [
                "I-PER",
                "I-PER",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-LOC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-LOC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O"
              ],
              "text": "Ibn Khurradādhbih ’ s document is unique evidence for the existence of organized long - distance trade between Europe and the east , both by land and sea , during a period when , it was long assumed , trade scarcely existed in Europe except on a regional basis ."
            },
            {
              "POS": [
                "ADV",
                "ADP",
                "PRON",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "PROPN",
                "PUNCT",
                "PROPN",
                "PROPN",
                "VERB",
                "NUM",
                "ADJ",
                "NOUN",
                "VERB",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "PROPN",
                "PROPN",
                "PUNCT",
                "CCONJ",
                "PROPN",
                "PUNCT",
                "NUM",
                "VERB",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "PROPN",
                "PROPN",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "PROPN",
                "PUNCT",
                "VERB",
                "ADP",
                "PROPN",
                "PUNCT",
                "DET",
                "ADJ",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "PROPN",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "PROPN",
                "PUNCT",
                "VERB",
                "ADP",
                "PROPN",
                "PUNCT"
              ],
              "labels": [
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-MISC",
                "O",
                "I-PER",
                "I-PER",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-MISC",
                "I-MISC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-MISC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-LOC",
                "I-LOC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-LOC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-LOC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-LOC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-LOC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-LOC",
                "O"
              ],
              "text": "Immediately after his description of the routes of the Rādhānīya , Ibn Khurradādhbih describes two northern routes followed by the Swedish Vikings , or Rūs , one leading to the Black Sea via the Dnieper , terminating in Constantinople , the other via the Volga to the Caspian , ending in Baghdad ."
            },
            {
              "POS": [
                "DET",
                "PROPN",
                "VERB",
                "ADP",
                "NOUN",
                "CCONJ",
                "NOUN",
                "PUNCT",
                "CCONJ",
                "AUX",
                "ADJ",
                "PART",
                "VERB",
                "ADP",
                "PROPN",
                "ADP",
                "PROPN",
                "PUNCT",
                "VERB",
                "NOUN",
                "ADV",
                "VERB",
                "ADV",
                "PUNCT"
              ],
              "labels": [
                "O",
                "I-MISC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-LOC",
                "O",
                "I-MISC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O"
              ],
              "text": "The Rūs traded in furs and swords , and were able to communicate in Baghdad with Slavic - speaking slaves already resident there ."
            },
            {
              "POS": [
                "CCONJ",
                "DET",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "PROPN",
                "CCONJ",
                "DET",
                "PROPN",
                "VERB",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "PROPN",
                "NOUN",
                "PUNCT"
              ],
              "labels": [
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-MISC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-MISC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-MISC",
                "O",
                "O"
              ],
              "text": "Both the routes of the Rādhānīya and the Rūs passed through the territory of the Khazar empire ."
            },
            {
              "POS": [
                "ADP",
                "PRON",
                "NOUN",
                "PROPN",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "PROPN",
                "NOUN",
                "PUNCT",
                "DET",
                "PROPN",
                "PUNCT",
                "PROPN",
                "PROPN",
                "VERB",
                "DET",
                "VERB",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "ADJ",
                "NOUN",
                "CCONJ",
                "VERB",
                "DET",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "ADJ",
                "PROPN",
                "CCONJ",
                "PROPN",
                "NOUN",
                "PUNCT"
              ],
              "labels": [
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-LOC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-LOC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-MISC",
                "I-MISC",
                "I-MISC",
                "I-MISC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-MISC",
                "O",
                "I-MISC",
                "O",
                "O"
              ],
              "text": "From their capital Itil in the Volga delta , the Judeo - Turkic Khazars dominated the emerging economies of the northern steppes and provided the template for the earliest Rūs and Slavic principalities ."
            },
            {
              "POS": [
                "X",
                "DET",
                "ADJ",
                "NOUN",
                "AUX",
                "VERB",
                "ADP",
                "ADJ",
                "NOUN",
                "PUNCT"
              ],
              "labels": [
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-MISC",
                "O",
                "O"
              ],
              "text": "2 The northern trade was fuelled by Islamic silver ."
            },
            {
              "POS": [
                "NOUN",
                "ADJ",
                "NOUN",
                "VERB",
                "ADP",
                "PROPN",
                "NOUN",
                "VERB",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "NOUN",
                "NOUN",
                "VERB",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "PROPN",
                "PROPN",
                "ADP",
                "PRON",
                "NOUN",
                "PUNCT",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "NOUN",
                "AUX",
                "AUX",
                "VERB",
                "ADP",
                "PROPN",
                "NOUN",
                "NOUN",
                "PUNCT"
              ],
              "labels": [
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-MISC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-MISC",
                "I-MISC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-MISC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O"
              ],
              "text": "Silver dirham coins struck in Abbasid mints flooded west along the trade routes opened by the Swedish Vikings in their millions ; hundreds of thousands have been found in Viking coin hoards ."
            },
            {
              "POS": [
                "ADJ",
                "AUX",
                "VERB",
                "ADP",
                "VERB",
                "NOUN",
                "PUNCT",
                "ADP",
                "PROPN",
                "CCONJ",
                "DET",
                "PROPN",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "PROPN",
                "PUNCT",
                "ADP",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "NOUN",
                "PUNCT",
                "NOUN",
                "PUNCT",
                "NOUN",
                "PUNCT",
                "NOUN",
                "CCONJ",
                "NOUN",
                "PUNCT"
              ],
              "labels": [
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-MISC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-LOC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-MISC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-LOC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O"
              ],
              "text": "Most were obtained by Viking traders , in Bulghār and the Khazar capital of Itil , in exchange for furs , slaves , honey , wax and amber ."
            },
            {
              "POS": [
                "ADV",
                "ADV",
                "PUNCT",
                "PRON",
                "AUX",
                "ADJ",
                "NOUN",
                "PRON",
                "VERB",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "ADJ",
                "NOUN",
                "PUNCT",
                "DET",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "PRON",
                "VERB",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "ADJ",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "PROPN",
                "PUNCT",
                "CCONJ",
                "PROPN",
                "PUNCT",
                "VERB",
                "NOUN",
                "PUNCT"
              ],
              "labels": [
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-MISC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-MISC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-MISC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O"
              ],
              "text": "Once again , it is Arabic sources that shed light on this lucrative trade , the profits from which led to the development of the first towns in Slavic - and Finnic - speaking regions ."
            },
            {
              "POS": [
                "PROPN",
                "CCONJ",
                "PROPN",
                "PUNCT",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "ADJ",
                "PUNCT",
                "ADJ",
                "PUNCT",
                "NOUN",
                "PUNCT",
                "AUX",
                "PRON",
                "ADV",
                "VERB",
                "ADP",
                "NOUN",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "PROPN",
                "PUNCT",
                "PROPN",
                "PUNCT",
                "PUNCT",
                "ADV",
                "VERB",
                "ADP",
                "NOUN",
                "PUNCT",
                "VERB",
                "PRON",
                "ADJ",
                "NOUN",
                "PUNCT"
              ],
              "labels": [
                "I-LOC",
                "O",
                "I-LOC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-MISC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-MISC",
                "O",
                "I-LOC",
                "I-ORG",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-MISC",
                "O",
                "O"
              ],
              "text": "Kiev and Novgorod , among the earliest ‘ Russian ’ towns , were both originally founded as trading posts by the Viking ‘ Rūs ’ , eventually developing into cities , losing their Viking character ."
            },
            {
              "POS": [
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "NOUN",
                "ADP",
                "DET",
                "ADJ",
                "NOUN",
                "PRON",
                "AUX",
                "VERB",
                "PROPN",
                "PUNCT",
                "VERB",
                "CCONJ",
                "PROPN",
                "PROPN",
                "ADP",
                "NOUN",
                "PUNCT"
              ],
              "labels": [
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O",
                "I-MISC",
                "O",
                "I-MISC",
                "O",
                "I-MISC",
                "I-MISC",
                "O",
                "O",
                "O"
              ],
              "text": "By the end of the tenth century they had become Slavic - speaking and Orthodox Christian in faith ."
            }
          ]
        ],
        "start": -1
      }
    ]
  },
  "book_index": "[{\"header\":\"Chapter 1\",\"page\":\"0\"}]"
}